CHANDRA SHEKAR REDDY GADIPALLY

1-312-282-4717 https://stackoverflow.com/users/6024518/c-s-reddy-gadipally

gcsr13@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/gcsreddy/

Saint Louis, MO, USA https://github.com/gcsreddy

https://gcsreddy.com

SUMMARY

Bachelors in Electronics and Computer Engineering. Masters in Computer Science. Apache Spark developer, data engineer for 3 years and full stack enterprise applications developer for 9 years.

Lightbend certified Scala Professional and Reactive Architect (see on Linkedin)

SKILLS

Docker

Programming languages	Big Data and Database	Web, Frameworks
Scala	Apache Spark	JavaEE
Haskell	Hadoop	Spring framework
Java	Hive	Struts2
Elm	Kafka	Play framework
JavaScript	Oracle RDBMS	Node, Express
С	DB2	REST, Micro services
SQL	MySQL	HTML5, CSS
Typescript	MongoDB	Bootstrap 4
R (intermediate)	Version control, build tools,	XML, XSLT, JSON
Python (intermediate)	IDE	Jquery
Shell Script	Git, CVS	JPA
Cloud, OS	Maven, Sbt, Gradle, NPM	MyBatis
Google, AWS	Jenkins.	Apache Tomcat
Linux. Windows	Vim. Eclipse. VSCode	Weblogic

WORK EXPERIENCE

Employer: Imbuesys Inc.

Contractor - Sr Software engineer

Edward Jones Investments, St. Louis Mar 2012 – Aug 2019.

Architect-ed, designed and developed Spark-Scala batch jobs to identify and describe Financial advisors' trends in account transfers and conversions, new accounts, commission based accounts' discount reduction or elimination, contributions, distributions, annual review events, portfolio objectives etc. Calculated Z-Scores of the aggregated data and compared against in house rules system to generate review items for financial supervision department's primary and advisory teams.

Required Minimum Distribution: Developed web application for Home office users and branches to perform Required minimum distribution calculation and generate reports.

Fee disclosure 1 & 3: Developed web application to help HQ users support notification to clients of qualified plans comply to DOL's regulation.

Dividend Reinvestment Program-Canada: Developed web application for Financial Advisors in Canada to start and stop stock dividend reinvestment of securities.

Financial Advisor performance: Developed rich client user interface to measure, calculate and show performance metrics and visualization using high-charts.

All account Fees: Developed web application to consolidate fee related legacy solutions for retirement, user managed and advisory accounts into a single platform to help expedite the process of creating new fee types. Used IBM DB2 Java stored procedures.

Contractor – Java developer

Caterpillar HQ, Peoria, IL. October 2011 - December 2011

Did Enhancements to TMIWeb (http://tmiweb.cat.com) using Spring MVC framework, Hibernate ORM framework, Java server pages, JQuery and JMesa tables.

Contractor - Java developer

Credit Suisse Investment Bank, NYC. March 2011 - September 2011

Global Stock record is a high volume, high performance ledger on which all security movements and positions are recorded. Used Drools rule engine to break incoming trade requests, implemented aggregation logic in java and improved performance by tuning indices and queries to process 8 million records per hour on a 4 node cluster. Used JMeter to simulate high loads.

Java Intern

Mars-telecom, Hyderabad. May 2008 – August 2008

Developed a proof of concept for AXA auto insurance using Cordys business process management tool.

Java Intern

Renaissance infotech, Hyderabad. January 2008 - May 2008

Developed a college portal using HTML, CSS, Java, JEE and MySQL.

EDUCATION

Masters in Computer Science. Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago. January 2009 - December 2010.

Graduate coursework: Science of Programming, Algorithms, Advanced database organization, Operating systems design and implementation, Analytical modeling and simulation of computer systems, Computer networks I & II, Software project management, Object oriented analysis and design.

Scholarship: Dean's International alliance scholarship of 9 credit hours.

Bachelors in Electronics and Computer Engineering. JNTU, Hyderabad, India. 2004 – 2008.

Undergraduate coursework: Numerical Methods, Solid state physics, C programming, Data structures, Mathematical Modeling and Simulation, Graph Theory, Probability and Statistics, Advanced Computer architecture, Software engineering, Artificial Intelligence, Artificial neural networks, Engineering mathematics 1 & 2.